# Danyang Zhuo

Assistant Professor Department of Computer Science Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Duke University

February 23, 2021 308 Research Dr Durham, NC 27705 danyang@cs.duke.edu https://danyangzhuo.com

#### Research Interests

I do research broadly in computer systems, including operating systems, distributed systems, and computer networks, with a focus on the design and implementation of data center systems to support today's increasingly data-intensive applications (e.g., deep learning, big data analytics, packet processing). My approaches include software architecture design, programming languages, and machine learning.

#### Education

 ${\bf University\ of\ Washington-Seattle}$ 

Seattle, Washington Sep 2013 - Aug 2019

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

- Dissertation: Practical, Efficient, and Reliable Data Center Communication.
- Advisors: Thomas E. Anderson, Arvind Krishnamurthy

University of Illinois - Urbana Champaign

Software Development Engineering Intern

B.S. in Electrical Engineering

Aug 2009 - May 2013

May 2012 - Aug 2012

Urbana, Illinois

Advisor: Nitin Vaidya

## **Professional Experience**

• Duke University • Assistant Professor of Computer Science	Durham, North Carolina Jul 2020 - now
<ul> <li>University of California – Berkeley</li> <li>Postdoctoral Researcher</li> <li>Advisor: Ion Stoica</li> </ul>	Berkeley, California Sep 2019 - Jun 2020
Microsoft Research  Contractor (through Populous Group)	Redmond, Washington Oct 2015 - Feb 2017
Microsoft Research Research Intern	Redmond, Washington  Jun 2015 - Sep 2015
• Google • Software Development Engineering Intern	Mountain View, California Sep 2014 - Mar 2015
• Amazon • Software Development Engineering Intern	Seattle, Washington May 2013 - Sep 2013
Microsoft	Redmond, Washington

#### **Publications**

### Conference Papers

- 1. Sitan Chen, Xiaoxiao Li, Zhao Song, Danyang Zhuo. On InstaHide, Phase Retrieval, and Sparse Matrix Factorization. The 9th International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2021.
- Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Mengqi Chen, Ryan Jennings, Ang Chen, Danyang Zhuo, Thomas Anderson. High Velocity Kernel File Systems with Bento. The 19th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST), 2021.
   Best Paper Award.
- 3. Lianmin Zheng, Chengfan Jia, Minmin Sun, Zhao Wu, Cody Hao Yu, Ameer Haj-Ali, Yida Wang, Jun Yang, Danyang Zhuo, Koushik Sen, Joseph E. Gonzalez, Ion Stoica. *Ansor: Generating High-Performance Tensor Programs for Deep Learning*. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI), 2020.
- 4. Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Arvind Krishnamurthy. Gallium: Automated Software Middlebox Offloading to Programmable Switches. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2020.
- 5. Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Aditya Akella, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Xi Wang. *Automated Verification of Customizable Middlebox Properties with Gravel.* The 17th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2020.
- Danyang Zhuo, Kaiyuan Zhang, Yibo Zhu, Hongqiang Harry Liu, Matthew Rockett, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network. The 16th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2019.
- 7. Danyang Zhuo, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Klaus-Tycho Förster, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. *Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center Networks*. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2017.
- 8. Danyang Zhuo, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, Xuan Kelvin Zou, Hang Guan, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. *RAIL: A Case for Redundant Arrays of Inexpensive Links in Data Center Networks*. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2017.
- 9. Vincent Liu, Danyang Zhuo, Simon Peter, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. Subways: A Case for Redundant, Inexpensive Data Center Edge Links. The 13th International Conference on emerging Networking EXperiments and Technologies (CoNEXT), 2015.

#### Workshop Papers

- Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Shibin Xu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. Practical Safe Linux Kernel Extensibility. The 17th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS), 2019.
- 2. Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Xin Yang, Vincent Liu. Canaries in the Network. The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.

- 3. Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Vincent Liu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. *Rack-level Congestion Control*. The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.
- 4. Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Dan Ports, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. *Machine Fault Tolerance for Reliable Datacenter Systems*. The 5th Asia-Pacific Workshop on Systems (APSys), 2014.

#### **Patents**

1. Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, Danyang Zhuo, Xuan Kelvin Zou. *Data Center Topology Having Multiple Classes of Reliability*. US Patent 20170302565A1. WIPO Patent 2017180450A1.

#### **Students**

#### **Current PhD Students**

Jingrong Chen (2020-), Guozhen She (2020-), Xinhao Kong (2021-)

### **Awards**

FAST Best Paper Award	2021
University of Washington Madrona Prize Runner-Up	2018
University of Washington Hacherl Endowed Fellowship	2014
Rank 146th in the William Lowell Putnam Mathematical Competition	2012

### **Invited Talk**

- ACM SIGCOMM

•	Towards	Efficient a	and	Reliable	Data	Center	Systems.
---	---------	-------------	-----	----------	------	--------	----------

- Yale University	$\mathrm{Apr}\ 2019$					
- Purdue University	Apr 2019					
- University of Virginia	Mar 2019					
- Duke University	Mar 2019					
- Rutgers University	Mar 2019					
- Microsoft Research	Mar 2019					
- Penn State University	Feb 2019					
- University of Minnesota	Feb 2019					
• Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network.						
- Princeton University	Jun 2020					
- USENIX NSDI	Feb 2019					

Aug 2017

• Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center Networks.

• RAIL: A Case for Redundant Arrays of Inexpensive Links in Data Center Networks.					
- USENIX NSDI	Mar 2017				
Teaching					
• CPS 510: Advanced Operating Systems. (Fall 2020)					
Service					

Program Committee

• SIGCOMM (2020)